hi guys welcome back to my channel my
name is Asa rosette if you're new here
thank you for joining and if you thank
you for sticking with me so in today's
video I'm going to be talking about the
best gels for locks for starting those
locks best gels for retwisting Palm
rolling the best gels if you have locks
and you don't really be dealing with
buildup this video is for you so make
sure you stay to the end so let's get
into it so if you have been following me
on here you'll know that I'm also
launching my own lock gel and I'm going
to be showing you a bit of the behind
scenes I didn't upload the video last
week and as you know it's because I was
doing a photo shoot for the launch of my
lockel which is launching next month so
if you haven't already subscribed to my
newsletter I to stay up to date with
details on what when I'll be launching
specifically what date and sign up the
link in my bio so let's get into
it so if you know if you have locks or
depending on I guess how many how far
you are within your lock Journey you
would know that a lot of lock heads
including myself included I've suffered
from a lot of buildup and the buildup IS
as a result of different things right
sometimes the buildup comes because of
our hair shedding its skin like um our
hair our scalp sometimes we have
dermatitis sometimes we got we have
flaky scalp sometimes the oils and the
buildup of our scalp the our natural
hairs oils it will go on our locks and
then we get build up from that but the
main ankles of build up sometimes you
might know it's to do with the gels that
we use so I remember when I first
started my lock journey and I was going
to hairon and they were using gel which
was amazing I love the slipback look I
like the the the I guess the whole
enhanced look that it gave me the only
issue is that when I wanted to now start
doing my own when I wanted to start
doing my own like maintenance on my
locks and I was trying to research on
the best lock gels I kept coming across
the um what is that lock gel called oh
my gosh
um lemon is it lemon and
lime but I remember hearing very
negative things because a lot of people
said they suffered build up as a result
of that particular gel and I was kind of
like confused I was thinking okay where
do I go from here where can I get like a
lock gel that actually gives me a nice
hold without actually giving me the
build up cuz what I found when I was
researching I came across other gels
which um did give me the hold um did
give me the no build up but didn't give
me the hold necessary
so I'll give you an example and I don't
actually have it here but lion locks was
one it gave me a a hold that lasted
maybe like a day um and depending I
guess for different people different
hair textures some are easier to hold
and others are not so much so lion locks
helped me as in not get the buildup
unfortunately I didn't get the hold that
I really wanted and I guess it depend on
you if you are someone that likes to you
know like much tighter hold or if
someone if you're someone that likes
that more manicured look with your locks
then perhaps line lock not be the one
for you but it didn't give me the
buildup and I also then tried Talia with
the tight hold one this um as you can
see I still got some um I've still got
some here I didn't use much of it I'd
say I used this within my uh maybe 3
four months in when I started my lock
Journey um it's kind of like a jelly
rather than a like a jelly rather than a
gel because it kind of let me actually
I'm going to you know I'm going to do
for the rest of the video I'm going to
take them out so as you can see this is
the
consistency it's kind of like a jelly
right and it's got this like whiteness
to it so if you rub it like this on your
skin I'm just going
to
demonstrate as you can see can you see
that it's got like a kind of like a
white
cast and so we this gel like I said in
fact I used this before I use the line
locks because I remember at the time I
thought okay let me find something that
doesn't give me build up so I used this
one
and it gave me the hold I'd say for
like maybe how long maybe like a week or
so the issue um that I found which
wasn't really the hold obviously was the
hold but for me it's not my biggest
problem area my biggest problem area is
um my biggest problem ever with this gel
was I had fak so within like a day I
have fak I had white stuff in my scalp
and it's one thing that I never
experienced when I was going to the
loctician so I thought oh my gosh what
is this um so yeah it gave me fck so
which is why I've still got like a full
bottle it doesn't
really it doesn't really give me the I
guess the desired look that I want
because I've got white stuff in my hair
on my looks um would I necessarily
recommend it for F braiding possibly not
cuz I don't feel like it gives you the
hold because even when you put on your
skin it doesn't really feel like that
gel consistency in fact this um I know I
me in fact I know I mentioned I'm
working on my um I'm launching a lock
gel so this in fact the consistency of
this when I was going through the
testing phase of my formulation um at
the beginning as you know if you ever
have started a lock product you or not
just not product a product in general
you know that when you're doing you have
to go through different phases to see
okay is this the formula the consistency
that I need that I require does it give
me the hold so I went through a phase
where I had one that was similar to this
so which brings me on to my next one
this was a it's
called what is it called I can't even
see the the name on here like a gel wax
it says maximum hold dark molding gel
wax just so you could
see um
unfortunately this gave me a b sever
build up because this is one that I also
saw like being it being used within my
my locticians so I'm not sure if they
still use it now but it gave me a lot of
buildup and I'll even come close so that
you could see perhaps the buildup on the
back of my locks the bottom ones this is
where I started
it so when I started my locks I started
with those can you see the the right
stuff there she like I say if you are
starting locks you want to make sure
that you're starting with a gel that
doesn't really cause a lot of this at
the beginning because now you're going
to do you're going to do yourself a
disservice then have to fix the problem
when it's about to kind of avoid the
problem entirely prevention is better
than cure this did it give me a nice
hold absolutely it's a gel wax it's
going to give you a good hold um it's
kind of like I guess it gives you the
kind of texture like gummy if for anyone
I mean if anyone of you guys have ever
used gummy for braids gives you that and
although it's amazing for braids I'm
sure this will probably be good for
braids cuz I do use it for my daughter's
braids when I'm doing like kind of
Corners going back unfortunately it also
F build up and I found out when I was
using it for my daughter's braids when
it came down to taking it out there was
a lot of Gunk that was stuck there and
I'm finding that I'm having to take a
little bit more time when it comes to
Cleansing her hair and so forth so I'm
just going to show you the
consistency that is the consistency
there that's the
color too much I don't know I too much
um that's the
color and if you were to I guess rub it
on your scalp SC on the back of your
hand you can see how it
applies so it doesn't really like rub
into the
skin it kind of sits on the skin and you
can only imagine it probably just sit on
on your hair um so yeah I'm going to
take it off I've got like a cloth here
I'm rubbing it off but again it feels
very like a very sticky residue if
you're an adult and you don't have a
Sensitive Scalp then it might work for
you um having to go through the process
of detangling if you got loose hair you
got locks now it might be a bit of a
challenge because there's only so much
and as I was washing my hair and I
squeeze I finally I see this all this
gunk coming out right I never
experienced it with the gel that I'm
about to show you
now so this was one that I've always
been very about um it's called my gel
Joy Naturals you might have seen it if
you've been watching any of my other
videos you might have seen
it on my um you might have seen it on my
one of my videos of me in my here I've
had it for a minute it's as you can see
this is the only one that I feel like I
haven't I haven't hit the bottom yet but
I'm nearly and it's lasted quite a bit
but anyways I don't really retwist my
hair that much so it little goes a long
way the only issue that I find with this
one is not with the buildup or anything
I think I paid £30 for this and now
30 is okay but for the amount that I'm
getting for I'm getting for it it's like
4 oz3 G would I necessarily want to keep
spending £30 for £13 G um 4 oz this is
like maybe 100 150 mil it's not 100 Mil
um not necessarily but I would I don't
mind spending that much if the if I'm
not getting build up which is why I
thought it's my first one I've never
actually bought another one because I
haven't finished this one but if I
wasn't launching my own lock gel I
probably would go back and buy this
because for me my locks are here to stay
for a lifetime and even if I'm going to
keep them for the next 5 10 years I want
to make sure that I try to avoid build
up entirely so you kind of have to
outweigh the pros and the Cons with
regards to the pricing I always feel
like I'm willing to spend that little
bit extra to make sure that my health
the health of my hair is intact and also
to make sure my hair still looks good
because the front bit now like all this
up to here I don't have build up it's
just these these bits that I have build
up because of this gel unfortunately so
this one it didn't give me the buildup
it's
just um it's just I guess at the time I
thought it was expensive but um would I
buy would I spend £30 again for 113 if I
couldn't find a gel that works and I
probably would so do I have anything
negative to say about this one no I
haven't um I don't actually have
anything like I said apart from the
price and the amount that I'm getting
for it then yes but aside from that I
feel like it gave me a good hold it
didn't when I washed my hair I didn't
feel that feeling where I have this so
much Gunk and like I said earlier in the
video you are going to experience build
up um not buildup but just product build
sometimes it's product buildup sometimes
the buildup isn't necessarily product
but it's your your natural shedding of
the hair along with the scalp with your
the your scalp that and it inter with
the lck so it's not always product build
up but you can kind of see where is
product build up depending and also when
you kind of I feel like the best way
that you can figure it out is by looking
at your product tting it putting it
under water and seeing does this
actually dissolve
well so that was this this your in myel
amazing right and then um
I came across a video one time this girl
I think her name was I can't her name
actually but I saw someone online that
said that they use a shine and jam gel
for
retwisting and I've never used it for
retwisting have I I think I've tried it
for like two front locks at the
beginning and it kind of gave me a good
consistency a good hold but um it's not
really a lock Jael I would say it's more
for braiders um does it give build up it
doesn't give buildup not again I've
never really tried with my locks but I
thought I'll put it in here just because
if you do have shin and jam at home give
you a try let me know what you think but
um I've just used on my daughter's hair
and I've used it for like the perimeter
of my locks and I haven't suffered build
up I just didn't get the hold that I
really needed for my locks um which
brings me onto my gel right so get a Dr
roll get drum roll who's I okay I've
been ring about it I'm so excited guys
can I get a drum roll please I've been
so excited about this it's taken a while
to get here but I'm finally glad that
we're finally here what I'm about to
show you is a sample size just because a
lot of the things and issues I already
had with the gels I wanted to make sure
that people are also getting value for
money you're also getting a balance of
the moisturization of your gel as long
as you hold with a gel without the
buildup without the flakes without the
white cast so get a j this is I said a
sample size so this is 100 Mil right but
this is not what you'll be getting
you'll be getting 250 mil with my gel
and I'll show you the other package just
below so this is
it see if
I um this is how it
looks again it's going to be very
different
after the size in creases initially I
was going to go for like a small size
but I thought you know what I like I
want to make sure that people are
getting a good amount a good amount so
I'll test it for you guys
so this is essentially
it this is the
gel so it's
clear it runs
clear I'm going to I'm going to come
closer um cuz I'm extra like that and I
want want to rub it in so you can see
how it rubs in
[Music]
my and I just want to move my hand like
this so that I can show you there's no
tacky feeling
either so it's like a combination of
um of a nice a nice balance you get like
the thickness that you would get if
you're trying to go for the the hold but
also making sure that you're still
nourishing your hair which is what I
believe the key to I guess healthy hair
is a healthy scalp um and you want to
make sure smells good and you want to
make sure that um you're not you're not
um I guess compromising the health of
your scalp because essentially you need
a good foundation to make sure your hair
is still grow grow growing um at its
optimal optimal rate and growth all
right so hence the name KU which means
growth in swah I speak so for those that
don't know um and care to entally care
for your hair's growth so um I feel like
often we go to we see we kind of go to
products that good are good when it goes
to styling um but we don't actually pay
attention to is this actually very
beneficial for my hair if you found me
through my 12 months lock transformation
video you'd see that I cut my hair and I
went completely bored and prior to when
I used to have loose hair I used to just
maintain it myself I never really went
to the C much but when I did which was
probably like twice if not three times
throughout the course of what 8 years I
went to get my hair braided I went to
get feeding braids and they used gum me
and for me it was my first time
obviously experiencing gumy I've always
seen in the shops but I've never used it
specifically on myself but what I find
found was going back to the story that I
mentioned regards to this show now which
gives me the same kind of hold and
consistency of gummy
if you've got locks or you've got loose
natural hair it takes a bit to it takes
a minute to now try and comb it out of
your hair I suffered a lot of like
breakage because of it and I don't want
to I don't want to create a gel that
gives people breakage when really you
can have both who says that you can't
style your hair and so make sure that
it's at its healthier State um so what
that's what I found GS that really are
very thick like gives you that waxy kind
of consistency you end up coming the
Heth of your hair um and then you end up
getting build build up and then in order
to kind of remove the build up whilst
you're going through detangling and
watching phase you find that your locks
are actually your not your locks your
hair you end up breaking your hair um as
a result and although I've got locks now
I remember that feeling and my
daughter's got hair so I remember the
feeling when I'm using this um this
particular gel on her hair in addition
to that um so with my gel I just I went
for me I wanted to do it to make sure
sure that even with locks I'm not
getting a white flake hence the reason
why I've done a lot of testing when I
was doing this one with the white cast
as you can see from the container itself
it's white which gave me the flakes um
this is my
jel and you see the I guess underneath
of the container it's see-through so you
can see that there is no white part it's
completely see-through um in fact I'll
open it again and I'll show you inside
I've been using my my gel as well so
it's completely secret right um so I
don't want to create a gel or product
that gives me a lot of the problem
things problem areas that I was exp the
other gels but I hope that has helped
and I also wanted to kind of show you
the behind the scenes of my lock product
photo shoot launch I don't know if I
told you guys but I was looking for lock
models and as a result I was trying to I
was I I was about to say I was
struggling but I hadn't actually put it
out there yet and then my sister so I
was like ASA why don't you just post a
Tik Tok video and I posted a Tik Tok
video and lo and behold I've got so many
people reach out to me um volunteering
to be I guess models for the launch of
my business so I was excited I hope I
can I hope you guys are just you know
share the same excitement that I have
for myself cuz trust and believe I am so
excited and a lot of people on here have
followed me for the very fact that I am
you know I'm a locked person who talks
about locks as well as the emotional
healing aspect but um this is my baby
guys and and I'm so excited to share it
with you because I've put in a lot of
work and effort and love into creating
this product and I hope that you guys
can actually see what's actually gone
into it I hope that once it launches
next month if you do purchase one give
me your honest feedback because I do
want to work on optimizing the
formulation as and when I get feedback
from you guys my first product I hope
that as time progresses I can increase
the cruiser care range to again work on
some of the challenges and the problem
areas that I've always experienced with
regards to
hair and I hope that it allows you to be
able to understand that you can
absolutely style your hair as of when
you know how you can do it in a way that
you want but without compromising the
health over your hair I feel like the
two can live together you can you can
create beautiful hair beautiful Styles
without actually affecting the health of
your your hair your locks and so forth
but yes this is my
baby um I'm excited I hope you guys are
too um
so this is
her this is her I'm just looking at my
monitor cuz I want to make sure I'm in
frame but this these are my baby girls K
care I don't know why I'm thinking of
they girls but they're baby girls yeah
kza care
and watch the space let me know guys if
you've made it this far thank you and
I'll see you in the next one
peace
for